Guide to the University of Chicago Department of Anthropology Records 1929-1997
University of Chicago Library
- Series X: Students
  - Subseries 1: Student Files
    - Lynn, Patricia M. 1954-1956 (Box 130, Folder 17)
    - Millman, Harry A. 1955-1956 (Box 130, Folder 18)
    - Miller, Patty Jean. 1955-1956 (Box 130, Folder 19)
    - Mohr, Barbara Lee, 1955-1956 (Box 130, Folder 20)
    - Mur'iby, Rasheed R., 1955-1956 (Box 130, Folder 21)
    - Okita, Fred Y. 1950-1956 (Box 130, Folder 22)
    - Pacyaya, Alfredo, 1955-1956 (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - Parry, Margaret Labudde, 1952, 1956 (Box 131, Folder 2)
    - Samuels, Sheldon, 1954-1956 (Box 131, Folder 3)
    - Shaw, Nancy R. 1956 (Box 131, Folder 4)
    - Sholund, Elvin Monroe, 1956 (Box 131, Folder 5)
    - Seltzer, Allan, 1956 (Box 131, Folder 6)
    - Skinner, Robert Roy, 1951-1956 (Box 131, Folder 7)
    - Smith, George H. 1945-1956 (Box 131, Folder 8)
    - Von Heeringen, Jochem, 1956 (Box 131, Folder 9)
    - Weisberg, Sydney R. 1956 (Box 131, Folder 10)
    - Weiss, Patricia Mae, 1956 (Box 131, Folder 11)
    - Albert, Roy D., 1955-1957 (Box 131, Folder 12)
    - Aoba, Tsuneo, 1957 (Box 131, Folder 13)
    - Bauxar, J. Joseph 1939-1957 (Box 131, Folder 14)
    - Beierle, John M. 1956-1957 (Box 131, Folder 15)
    - Blumberg, James Avrom, 1941-1957 (Box 131, Folder 16)
    - Brooke, Ronald Louis, 1956-1957 (Box 131, Folder 17)
    - Brown, Ann, 1956-1957 (Box 131, Folder 18)
    - Buettner, Janusch, John. 1949-1957 (Box 131, Folder 19)
    - Owyer, Barbara R. 1956-1957, undated (Box 131, Folder 20)
    - Falkenburg, Patricia A.B. 1956-1957 (Box 131, Folder 21)
    - Van Dusen Gale, Charles, 1957 (Box 131, Folder 22)
    - Gerasimo, Jerry, 1952-1957 (Box 131, Folder 23)
    - Gosda, Raymond Chester, 1949-1957 (Box 131, Folder 24)
    - Hale, Lloyd A. [handwritten addition: "Transferred to Law Sch.], 1954-1957 (Box 131, Folder 25)
    - Hamilton, James William. 1954-1957 (Box 131, Folder 26)
    - Han, Ma Nyunt. 1957 (Box 131, Folder 27)
    - Hurt, Wesley. 1948, 1957 (Box 132, Folder 1)
    - Johns, Bruce Sterling, 1953-1957 (Box 132, Folder 2)
    - Kelbert, Mary T. [Handwritten Addition: Hale] 1949, 1954-1957 (Box 132, Folder 3)
    - Lewis, Phillip M. (Papers), 1957 (Box 132, Folder 4)
    - Maceda, Jose. 1957 (Box 132, Folder 5)
    - Marty-Torres, Herbert. 1944-1957 (Box 132, Folder 6)
    - Maxwell, Moreau Sanford, 1941-1957 (Box 132, Folder 7)
    - Moore, Randolph Jordan, 1956-1957 (Box 132, Folder 8)
    - Park, George Kerling, 1952-1957 (Box 132, Folder 9)
    - Riley, William Joseph, 1955-1957 (Box 132, Folder 10)
    - Segundo, Thomas, 1953-1957 (Box 132, Folder 11)
    - Grant, Barbara Jean [Handwritten Addition: Sibley], 1955-1957 (Box 132, Folder 12)
    - Smith, Beverly Ann, 1956-1957 (Box 132, Folder 13)
    - Smith, J. Robin Sommers, 1957 (Box 132, Folder 14)
    - Tomasevich, George V. 1954-1957 (Box 132, Folder 15)
    - Vidyarthi, Lalita P. [2nd Folder], 1955-1957 (Box 132, Folder 16)
    - Wallace, J. Robert, 1955-1957 (Box 133, Folder 1)
    - Wenner, David J. Jr., 1949-1957 (Box 133, Folder 2)
    - Weston, Dwight, 1951-1957 (Box 133, Folder 3)
    - Angell, Elissa, 1958 (Box 133, Folder 4)
    - Atherton, Maryanne, B. 1955-1958 (Box 133, Folder 5)
    - Becker, Herbert, 1954-1958 (Box 133, Folder 6)
    - Bergman, Barry D. 1958 (Box 133, Folder 7)
    - Birdwhistell, Ray L. 1942-1958 (Box 133, Folder 8)
    - Blackburn, Frank. 1957-1958 (Box 133, Folder 9)
    - Brackett, Joseph Albert, 1957-1958 (Box 133, Folder 10)
    - Burclaw, Ellis, 1947-1949, 1958 (Box 133, Folder 11)
    - Cowgill, George, 1954-1958 (Box 133, Folder 12)
    - Emrich, Robert 1957-1958 (Box 133, Folder 13)
    - Ellison, Jack Lambert, 1957-1958 (Box 133, Folder 14)
    - Flint, Barry 1958 (Box 133, Folder 15)
    - Hamilton, Phillis M.T. 1947-1958 (Box 133, Folder 16)
    - Laviolette, Forrest E. 1958 (Box 133, Folder 17)
    - Lazarus, Beverly, 1958 (Box 133, Folder 18)
    - Marlin, Joseph R. 1954-1958 (Box 133, Folder 19)
    - Meisner, Larraine 1955-1958 (Box 133, Folder 20)
    - Mudd, Margaret Clark 1952-1958 (Box 133, Folder 21)
    - Munoz, Muna 1947, 1958 (Box 133, Folder 22)
    - McPherron, Alan, 1958 (Box 133, Folder 23)
    - McPherron, Stace 1950-1958 (Box 133, Folder 24)
    - Orr, Kenneth Gordon, 1942-1958 (Box 134, Folder 1)
    - Pairault, Claude Albert, 1955-1958 (Box 134, Folder 2)
    - Passin, Herbert, 1937-1941, 1951-1958 (Box 134, Folder 3)
    - Peske, G. Richard, 1958 (Box 134, Folder 4)
    - Pichardo, Mario, 1956-1958 (Box 134, Folder 5)
    - Savard, George Clovis, 1956-1958 (Box 134, Folder 6)
    - Spoehr, Alexander 1938-1941, 1958 (Box 134, Folder 7)
    - Tappen, Neil Campbell, 1949-1958 (Box 134, Folder 8)
    - Wilmink, Mary Barbara, 1951-1952, 1958 (Box 134, Folder 9)
    - Harris, Alfred II, 1949-1959 (Box 134, Folder 10)
    - Mayers, Marvin K.- CV and Grades, 1959 (Box 134, Folder 11)
    - Mendelson, Edward Michael, 1951-1959 (Box 134, Folder 12)
    - Nash, Manning, 1949-1959 (Box 134, Folder 13)
    - Starr, Betty Warren, 1948-1959 (Box 135, Folder 1)
    - Tax, Susan, 1957, 1959 (Box 135, Folder 2)
    - Thayer, Helen A. 1950-1959 (Box 135, Folder 3)
    - Wagner, Thomas H. III, 1959 (Box 135, Folder 4)
    - Werdenhoff, Charles, 1958-1959 (Box 135, Folder 5)
    - Zingg, Robert Mowry, 1930-1933, 1939-1949, 1959 (Box 135, Folder 6)
    - Barth, Thomas F.W., 1946-1960 (Box 135, Folder 7)
    - Bluhm, Elaine, 1946-1960 (Box 135, Folder 8)
    - Bowman, Elizabeth, 1960 (Box 135, Folder 9)
    - Donoghue, John D. 1951-1960 (Box 135, Folder 10)
    - Firestone, Homer L. 1951-1960 (Box 135, Folder 11)
    - Harvey, Byron III, 1952-1960 (Box 135, Folder 12)
    - Hokanson, Leonard, 1950-1951, 1960 (Box 135, Folder 13)
    - Lyman, Thomas A. 1950-1960 (Box 135, Folder 14)
    - Meeker, Marchia, 1941-1960 (Box 135, Folder 15)
    - Nurge, Ethel D. 1950-1960 (Box 135, Folder 16)
    - Shand, Anna Frances, 1958-1960 (Box 135, Folder 17)
    - Sutton, Virginia H. 1935-1937, 1960 (Box 135, Folder 18)
    - Alpenfels, Ethel J. 1944-1961 (Box 136, Folder 1)
    - Blackbird, Edith Veronica, 1958-1961 (Box 136, Folder 2)
    - Kirk, Quentin, 1957-1961 (Box 136, Folder 3)
    - Bowers, Alfred William, 1946-1962 (Box 136, Folder 4)
    - Collette, Patricia, 1947, 1962 (Box 136, Folder 5)
    - Gearing, Frederick O. 1954-1962 (Box 136, Folder 6)
    - Gray, Roberts F. 1948-1962 (Box 136, Folder 7)
    - Polgar, Stephen, 1951-1962 (Box 136, Folder 8)
    - Vidyarthi, Lalita P. 1956-1958, 1962 [1986] (Box 136, Folder 9)
    - Fox, Robert Bradford, 1951-1963 (Box 136, Folder 10)
    - Gutkind, Peter Claus W. 1949-1963 (Box 136, Folder 11)
    - Malloy, William Thomas, 1941-1963 (Box 136, Folder 12)
    - Murra, John Victor, 1941-1963 (Box 136, Folder 13)
    - Nettleslip, Martin A. 1956-1963 (Box 137, Folder 1)
    - Pehrson, Robert N. 1949-1963 (Box 137, Folder 2)
    - Sibley, Willis E. 1952-1963 (Box 137, Folder 3)
    - White, "Henny" P [Several Included Materials refer to Perkins, Mary Allen], 1949-1963 (Box 137, Folder 4)
    - Schmitt, Karl, 1940-1964 (Box 137, Folder 5)
    - Shack, William Alfred 1955-1964 (Box 137, Folder 6)
    - Wax, Rosalie Hankey, 1944-1964 (Box 137, Folder 7)
    - Callender, Charles Dean [Folder #1], 1958-1965 (Box 137, Folder 8)
    - Kasdan, Donna Bodholdt, 1953-1955, 1965, undated (Box 137, Folder 9)
    - Talbott, George A. III, 1952-1955, 1965 (Box 137, Folder 10)
    - Duggleby, Hester Sewell, 1947-1966 (Box 137, Folder 11)
    - Lewis, Phillip H. 1950-1956, 1964-1966 (Box 138, Folder 1)
    - Watson, Virginia Drew, 1958-1966 (Box 138, Folder 2)
    - Keining, Priscilla Copeland, 1941-1967 (Box 138, Folder 3)
    - Spiegel, Jerry Allen, 1956, 1967 (Box 138, Folder 4)
    - Roberts, Robert Edward T. 1938-1968 (Box 138, Folder 5)
    - Ball, Jean, 1943-1945, 1971 (Box 138, Folder 6)
    - Tubesing, Richard L. 1972 (Box 138, Folder 7)
    - Caldwell, Joseph R. [Folder #1], 1945-1974 (Box 138, Folder 8)
    - Farber, Ada Sachs, 1952-1974 (Box 138, Folder 9)
    - Fallers, Lloyd Ashton, 1950-1974 (Box 138, Folder 10)
    - Opler, Morris Edward, 1949, 1958, 1976 (Box 138, Folder 11)
    - Collier, Malcolm Carr, 1938-1983 (Box 139, Folder 1)
    - Krogman, Wilton, 1959, 1988 [Obituary] (Box 139, Folder 2)
    - Laves, Gerhardt K. 1944, 1988 (Box 139, Folder 3)
    - Baldwin, Martha, undated (Box 139, Folder 4)
    - Barrows, David Prescott, undated (Box 139, Folder 5)
    - Frey, Mary Elizabeth R. undated (Box 139, Folder 6)
    - Garrison, Jane [Handwritten Addition: Mrs. Stretcher], undated (Box 139, Folder 7)
    - Geller, Esther, undated (Box 139, Folder 8)
    - Gibson, Bethune M. undated (Box 139, Folder 9)
    - Goodwin, Grenville, undated (Box 139, Folder 10)
    - Gordon, Tania, undated (Box 139, Folder 11)
    - Griffith, Edgar C. undated (Box 139, Folder 12)
    - Harding, Anne D. undated (Box 139, Folder 13)
    - Hauf, Gloria Jane, undated (Box 139, Folder 14)
    - Kerner, Oliver J.B. undated (Box 139, Folder 15)
    - Lehmer, Mary S. undated (Box 139, Folder 16)
    - Leviton, Charlotte, undated (Box 139, Folder 17)
    - Levy, Katherine, undated (Box 139, Folder 18)
    - Lichtenberg, Clare V. undated (Box 139, Folder 19)
    - Maclean, Kathleen, undated (Box 139, Folder 20)
    - McRoy, George R. undated (Box 139, Folder 21)
    - Newton, Donald A. undated (Box 139, Folder 22)
    - Nogueira, Oracy, undated (Box 139, Folder 23)
    - Reining, Priscilla Copeland- papers/CV, undated (Box 139, Folder 24)
    - Rodgers, Robert R. undated (Box 139, Folder 25)
    - Smither, Robert Ray- CV, undated (Box 139, Folder 26)
    - Wilson, gold Refined, undated (Box 139, Folder 27)
    - Service, Elman R. undated (Box 139, Folder 28)
  - Subseries 2: Exams
    - Master's Qualifying Exam, General Anth. Baer-Marriot, 1948 (Box 140, Folder 1)
    - Master's Qualifying Exam, General Anth. Messinger-Steinbeck, 1948 (Box 140, Folder 2)
    - Social Anthropology Exam, 1948 (Box 140, Folder 3)
    - Master's Qualifying Exam, Barth-Jones, 1948 (Box 140, Folder 4)
    - Master's Qualifying Exam, Keller-Merrill, 1948 (Box 140, Folder 5)
    - Master's Qualifying Exam, Planalp-Rietz, 1948 (Box 140, Folder 6)
    - Master's Qualifying Exam, Reutz-Wolffson, 1948 (Box 140, Folder 7)
    - Master's Qualifying Exam, 1948 (Box 140, Folder 8)
    - Social Anthropology, 1948 (Box 140, Folder 9)
    - Physical Anthropology, 1948 (Box 140, Folder 10)
    - Master's Exam- Summer 1948 (Box 140, Folder 11)
    - Master's Qualifying Exam- June Morning, Adams-Hagen, 1949 (Box 140, Folder 12)
    - Master's Qualifying Exam, June Morning, Jones-Wresinder, 1949 (Box 141, Folder 1)
    - Master's Qualifying Exam, Afternoon, Adams-Hagen, 1949 (Box 141, Folder 2)
    - Master's Qualifying Exam, Afternoon, Jones-Wresinder, June 1949 (Box 141, Folder 3)
    - Master's Final Exam, Social Anthropology Spring 1949 (Box 141, Folder 4)
    - Master's Final Exam, Physical Anthropology, Spring 1949 (Box 141, Folder 5)
    - Anthropology General Exam, Morning, Ballinger-Gosda, Fall 1950 (Box 141, Folder 6)
    - Anthropology General Exam, Morning, Gutkind-Turner, Fall 1950 (Box 141, Folder 7)
    - Anthropology General Exam Afternoon, Ballinger-Gosda, Fall 1950 (Box 141, Folder 8)
    - Anthropology General Exam, Afternoon, Gutkind-Turner, Fall 1950 (Box 141, Folder 9)
    - Social Anthropology and Archeology Exam, Fall 1950 (Box 141, Folder 10)
    - General Anthropology, Morning Question #1: Adams-Lewis, Spring 1950 (Box 142, Folder 1)
    - General Anthropology, Morning Question #1: Lifeschultz-Wisdom, Spring 1950 (Box 142, Folder 2)
    - General Anthropology, Morning Question #2: Adams-Lifeshultz, Spring 1950 (Box 142, Folder 3)
    - General Anthropology, Morning Question #2: Mahoney-Wisdom, Spring, 1950 (Box 142, Folder 4)
    - General Anthropology, Afternoon: Adams-Johnson, Spring 1950 (Box 142, Folder 5)
    - General Anthropology, Afternoon: Kaplan-Wisdom, Spring 1950 (Box 142, Folder 6)
    - General Anthropology, Afternoon Question#4: Adams-Lifeschultz, Spring 1950 (Box 142, Folder 7)
    - General Anthropology Afternoon Question #4: Mahoney-Wisdom, Spring 1950 (Box 143, Folder 1)
    - Social Anthropology: Allen-Hewitt, June 1950 (Box 143, Folder 2)
    - Social Anthropology: Kaplan-Wisdom, June 1950 (Box 143, Folder 3)
    - General Exams, 1951-1957 (Box 143, Folder 4)
    - M.A. Qualifying Exam, 1958 (Box 143, Folder 5)
    - Anthropology General Exam, 1958 (Box 143, Folder 6)
    - General Exam, 1959 (Box 143, Folder 7)
    - General Exam, 1960 (Box 143, Folder 8)
    - General Exam, 1961 (Box 143, Folder 9)
    - General Exam, 1962 (Box 143, Folder 10)
    - General Exam, 1963 (Box 143, Folder 11)
    - General Exam, 1964 (Box 143, Folder 12)
    - General Exam, 1965 (Box 143, Folder 13)
    - General Exam Retake, 1962-1965 (Box 143, Folder 14)
    - Make-Up Exams, 1965 (Box 143, Folder 15)
    - General Exam, 1966 (Box 144, Folder 1)
    - Written Exam, Etc. 1962-1979 (Box 144, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 3: Grades
    - Taylor, Herbert C. Jr.: Misc. Term Papers and Review Notes, 1950-1951 (Box 144, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous papers, Pehrson, Robert N; Starr, Betty and Nancy Oestreich; Jacoba, Alan H; Britan, Norman; 1948-1951 (Box 144, Folder 4)
    - Time Sheets, 1956-1959 (Box 144, Folder 5)
    - Registrar- Correspondence, 1950-1961 (Box 144, Folder 6)
    - Students in Other Departmets, 1958-1961 (Box 144, Folder 7)
    - Registration for Exams and Evaluation of Students (Incomplete), 1946-1961 (Box 144, Folder 8)
    - Class Rosters, 1961-1962 (Box 144, Folder 9)
    - Class Roster, Winter, 1963 (Box 144, Folder 10)
    - Class Roster, 1964-1965 (Box 144, Folder 11)
  - Subseries 4: Aid and Awards
    - Phi Beta Kappa, 1951-1957 (Box 145, Folder 1)
    - Menges, Karl H.- SSRC Grant Application, 1959 (Box 145, Folder 2)
    - Student Assistant (and Assistance), 1958-1959 (Box 145, Folder 3)
    - Sigma Xi, Nominations, 1937-1960 (Box 145, Folder 4)
    - Student Aid, 1958-1960 (Box 145, Folder 5)
    - Committee of New Nations, 1960-1967 (Box 145, Folder 6)
    - Student Scholarship Competition Questionnaire, 1967 (Box 145, Folder 7)
    - Sigma Xi, Nomination Blanks, 1963-1969 (Box 145, Folder 8)
    - Recommendation Lists (For Graduate Grants), 1968-1969 (Box 145, Folder 9)
    - Student Aid and Funding Information, 1958-1970 (Box 145, Folder 10)
    - Aid (Student), 1973 (Box 145, Folder 11)
    - Committee On Graduate Student Affairs, 1970-1980 (Box 145, Folder 12)
  - Subseries 5: Jobs and Recommendations
    - Jobs Available and Recommendations, 1957-1959 (Box 146, Folder 1)
    - Jobs Available and Recommendations, 1960-1961 (Box 146, Folder 2)
    - Jobs Available and Recommendations, 1962-1963 (Box 146, Folder 3)
    - Jobs Available and Recommendations, 1963-1964 (Box 146, Folder 4)
    - Jobs Available and Recommendations, 1964-1965 (Box 146, Folder 5)
    - Jobs Available and Recommendations, 1965-1966 (Box 146, Folder 6)
    - Jobs Available and Recommendations, 1967-1968 (Box 146, Folder 7)
    - Jobs Available and Recommendations, 1968-1969 (Box 146, Folder 8)
    - Jobs Available and Recommendations, 1969-1970 (Box 146, Folder 9)
    - Jobs Available and Recommendations, 1970-1971 (Box 146, Folder 10)
    - Jobs Available and Recommendations, 1971-1972 (Box 146, Folder 11)
    - Jobs Available and Recommendations, 1972-1973 (Box 146, Folder 12)
    - Jobs Available and Recommendations, 1973-1974 (Box 146, Folder 13)
    - Jobs Available and Recommendations, 1973-1974 (Box 146, Folder 14)
    - Jobs Needed, 1958-1960 (Box 146, Folder 15)